<?xml version="1.0" standalone="no"?><!DOCTYPE s1 SYSTEM
"./dtd/document.dtd">
<s1 title="Document Object Model Level 3 Implementation">
<s2 title="Disclaimer">
<p>
The &ParserNameLong; &ParserVersion;  contains a partial implementation of the W3C Document Object Model 
Level 3.  This implementation is experimental.  The DOM Level 3 specification is 
still in working draft stage: you should not consider this implementation complete or correct.  
The limitations of this implementation are detailed below. 
Please, read this document before using dom3 package.  
</p>
</s2> 
<s2 title="Introduction">
<p>
The &ParserNameLong; &ParserVersion; contains an implementation of a subset of the W3C DOM Level 3 as 
specified in <jump
href="http://www.w3.org/TR/2001/WD-DOM-Level-3-Core-20010913/">Core</jump>, <jump
href="http://www.w3.org/TR/2001/WD-DOM-Level-3-ASLS-20011025/abstract-schemas.html">Abstract 
Schemas</jump> and <jump
href='http://www.w3.org/TR/2001/WD-DOM-Level-3-ASLS-20011025/load-save.html'>Load 
and Save</jump>.  
</p>
<note>DOM Level 3 interfaces are located in org.apache.xerces.dom3 package</note>
</s2>

<s2 title='Implementation of DOM Level 3 Core'>
<ul>
    <li>
        DOMImplementationRegistry (see DOMImplementationSource)
    </li>
    <li>
        DOMImplementationRegistry (DOMImplementationSource really)
    </li>
    <li>
        Node.isSameNode()
    </li>
    <li>
        Node.getInterface()
    </li>
    <li>
        Node.set/getUserData()
    </li>
    
    <li>
        Node.isEqualNode()
    </li>
    <li>
        DOMErrorHandler, DOMError, DOMLocator
    </li>
</ul>
</s2> <s2 title='Implementation of DOM Level 3 Load and Save'>
<ul>
    <li>
        DOMBuilder - supports all required features. Does not provide implementation to 
        parseWithContext() and DOMBuilderFilter.
    </li>
    <li>
        DOMWriter - supports all required features. Provides support for "format-pretty-print" (true).
        DOMWriter also fixes namespaces during serialization as required by Load and Save module:

        "Namespaces are fixed up during serialization, the serialization process will verify that namespace declarations, namespace prefixes and the namespace URIs associated with Elements and Attributes are consistent. 
        If inconsistencies are found, the serialized form of the document will be altered to 
        remove them"    
        
        </li>
    <li>
        DOMInputSource
    </li>
    <li>
        DocumentLS
    </li>
    <li>
        DOMImplementationLS
    </li>
</ul>
</s2> <s2 title='Implementation of DOM Level 3 Abstract Schemas'>
<note>Xerces does not provide implementation for editing schemas (AS-EDIT) nor we provide implementation
for "Document-editing"</note>
<ul>
    <li>
        DOMImplementationAS
    </li>
    <li>
        DOMASBuilder that allows to preparse XML Schemas and set those on the parser.
    </li>
</ul>
<note>
DOMASBuilder only allows pre-parsing of XML Schemas. The parser provides a partial implementation for <code>ASModel</code> so that it can serve as a containter for several grammars. For more information, see dom.ASBuilder sample.
</note>
</s2></s1>
