<?xml version="1.0" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE faqs SYSTEM "sbk:/style/dtd/faqs.dtd">

<faqs title="Common Problems">
	<faq title="Parsing Generated an Error">
		<q>I tried to use Xerces-J to parse HTML, and it generated an error. What did I do wrong?</q>
		<a><p>Unfortunately, HTML does not, in general, follow the XML grammar rules. 
              Most HTML is actually not well-formed XML. Therefore, the XML parser 
			  generates XML well-formedness errors.</p>
			  <p>Typical errors include:</p>
              <ul>
                <li>Missing end tags, e.g. &lt;P&gt; with no &lt;/P&gt; (end tags are not required in HTML)</li>
                <li>Missing closing slash on &lt;IMG HREF="foo" <em>/</em>&gt; (not required in HTML)</li>
                <li>Missing quotes on attribute values, e.g. &lt;IMG width="600"&gt; (not generally required in HTML)</li>
              </ul>
		</a>
	</faq>
	<faq title="UTF-8 Character Error">
		<q>I get an error: &quot;invalid UTF-8 character&quot;</q>
		<a><p>There are many Unicode characters that are not allowed in an XML document, 
              according to the XML spec. Typical disallowed characters are control 
			  characters, even if you escape them using the Character Reference form: 
			  &amp;#xxxx; . See the XML spec, sections 
			  <jump href="http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-xml#charsets">2.2</jump> and 
			  <jump href="http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-xml#sec-references">4.1</jump> 
			  for details. If the parser is generating this error, it is very likely 
			  that there's a character in there that you can not see.
              You can generally use a UNIX command like &quot;od -hc&quot; to find it.</p>
			  
		</a>
	</faq>
	<faq title="Error Accessing EBCDIC XML Files">
		<q>I get an error when I access EBCDIC XML files -- what's happening?</q>
		<a><p>If an XML document/file is not UTF-8, then you MUST specify the encoding. 
              When transcoding a UTF8 document to EBCDIC, remember to change this:</p>
              <ul>
                <li>&lt;?xml version=&quot;1.0&quot; encoding=&quot;UTF-8&quot;?&gt; 
				<br/>to something like this:
				<br/>&lt;?xml version=&quot;1.0&quot; encoding=&quot;ebcdic-cp-us&quot;?&gt;
				</li>
              </ul>
		</a>
	</faq>
	<faq title="EOF Character Error">
		<q>I get an error on the EOF character (0x1A) -- what's happening?</q>
		<a><p>No, the parser isn't broken. You're probably using the <em>LPEX</em> 
		editor, which automatically inserts an End-of-file character at the end of your 
		XML document (other editors might do this as well). Unfortunately, the 
		EOF character (0x1A) is an illegal character according to the XML specification, 
		and Xerces-J correctly generates an error.</p>
		</a>
	</faq>
</faqs>
