<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE faqs SYSTEM 'dtd/faqs.dtd'>
<faqs title='Parser Configuration, Features and Properties FAQs'>
 <faq title='Validation Components'>
  <q>What's the result of having a DTD validator or XML Schema validator in the pipeline?</q>
  <a>
   <p>
    If a validator is included in the pipeline, assessment is
    done, whether the validation feature is set to true or false.
    Currently, validation only enables the validation constraint error reporting. The validation feature does not control the infoset augmentation: if a validator is included in the pipeline the parser will augment the infoset according to the grammar specified for the instance document. This behaviour may be revisited/changed in the future.
   </p>
  </a>
 </faq>
 <faq title='Default Parser Configuration'>
  <q>What validation behavior do I expect from the default parser configuration?</q>
  <a>
   <p>
    The default configuration includes both DTD validator and XML
    schema validator, so it's capable of validating an instance
    against both kinds of grammars.  But this could bring some
    performance hit for those applications that only process XML
    documents with DTD.  If you care about performance, and only
    use DTD, please use DTD configuration instead.
   </p>
  </a>
 </faq>
 <faq title='Validation Features'>
  <q>What happens if I set both validation and schema validation features on?</q>
  <a>
   <p>
     If only one of DTD validation and XML Schema validator
     is present in the pipeline, then we only consider the
     feature corresponding to this validator, and ignore the
     other one.
   </p>
   <p>
     If both validators are present in the pipeline, then
   </p>
   <ul>
    <li>if the instance document has only a DTD grammar
        (DOCTYPE before the root element), then only DTD
        validation errors are reported;</li>
    <li>if the instance document has only XML Schema grammars,
        then only XML Schema validation errors are reported
        (we consider an instance document to have a XML Schema
         grammar if either xsi:schemaLocation or
         xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation attribute is present
         on the root element. This might change after we
         support grammar caching);</li>
    <li>if the instance document has both DTD and XML Schema
        grammars, validation errors for both DTD and XML
        Schema are reported;</li>
    <li>if no grammar can be found for the instance document,
        then XML Schema validation errors are reported.</li>
   </ul>
   <p>
     NOTE: The above is the current interpretation of the
           validation features.  It may change in future
           Xerces releases.
   </p>
  </a>
 </faq>
 <faq title='External Schema Location Properties'>
  <q>Where are the two schema location properties introduced in Xerces 1?</q>
  <a>
   <p>
     External schema location properties are not currently
     supported in Xerces 2.  We're examining how to support
     this for the next Schema release.
    </p>
  </a>
 </faq>
</faqs>
