<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE properties SYSTEM 'dtd/settings.dtd'>
<properties>
 <desc name='Setting Properties'>
  <p>
   If you have created a DOM document builder or a SAX parser using
   the JAXP interfaces, you may have difficulty setting features and
   properties directly using those interfaces. The following
   instructions tell you how to set properties on document builders
   and SAX parsers created from the JAXP interfaces.
  </p>
  <p>
   The DocumentBuilderFactory interface contains a 
   <code>setAttribute(String,Object)</code> method which <em>may</em>
   provide a means to set features and properties on the underyling
   parser. However, it cannot be relied upon. Therefore, you must
   use the Xerces DOMParser object directly. For example:
  </p>
  <source>import org.apache.xerces.parsers.DOMParser;
import org.xml.sax.SAXException;
  
DOMParser parser = new DOMParser();

String id    = "http://apache.org/xml/properties/dom/document-class-name";
Object value = "org.apache.xerces.dom.DocumentImpl";
try {
    parser.setProperty(id, value);
} 
catch (SAXException e) {
    System.err.println("could not set parser feature");
}</source>
  <p>
   Using the SAXParser interface in JAXP is better because you can
   query the underlying XMLReader implementation directly and that
   interface contains methods to set and query features and 
   properties. For example:
  </p>
  <source>import javax.xml.parsers.SAXParser;
import org.xml.sax.SAXException;
import org.xml.sax.XMLReader;

SAXParser parser = /* created from SAXParserFactory */;
XMLReader reader = parser.getXMLReader();

String id    = "http://apache.org/xml/properties/dom/document-class-name";
Object value = "org.apache.xerces.dom.DocumentImpl";
try {
    reader.setProperty(id, value);
} 
catch (SAXException e) {
    System.err.println("could not set parser feature");
}</source>
 </desc>
 <pcategory name='General Properties'>
  <property name='http://xml.org/sax/properties/xml-string'
            id='xml-string'>
   <desc>
    Get the string of characters associated with the current event. 
    If the parser recognizes and supports this property but is not
    currently parsing text, it should return null.  
   </desc>
   <type>java.lang.String</type>
   <access general='read-only'/>
   <note>
    This property is currently not supported because the contents of
    the XML string returned by this property is not well defined.  
   </note>
  </property>
  <property name='http://apache.org/xml/properties/schema/external-schemaLocation'
            id='schema.external-schemaLocation'>
   <desc>
    The XML Schema Recommendation explicitly states that the inclusion
    of schemaLocation/noNamespaceSchemaLocation attributes is only a 
    hint; it does not mandate that these attributes must be used to 
    locate schemas. Similar situation happens to &lt;import&gt; element in
    schema documents. This property allows the user to specify a list of
    schemas to use. If the targetNamespace of a schema (specified 
    using this property) matches the targetNamespace of a schema 
    occurring in the instance document in schemaLocation attribute, or
    if the targetNamespace matches the namespace attribute of &lt;import&gt;
    element, the schema specified by the user using this property will
    be used (i.e., the schemaLocation attribute in the instance document
    or on the &lt;import&gt; element will be effectively ignored).
   </desc>
   <type>java.lang.String</type>
   <access general='read-write'/>
   <note>
    The syntax is the same as for schemaLocation attributes in 
    instance documents: e.g, "http://www.example.com file_name.xsd". 
    The user can specify more than one XML Schema in the list.   
   </note>
  </property>
  <property name='http://apache.org/xml/properties/schema/external-noNamespaceSchemaLocation'
            id='schema.external-noNamespaceSchemaLocation'>
   <desc>
    This property allows the user to specify an XML Schema with no 
    namespace.
   </desc>
   <type>java.lang.String</type>
   <access general='read-write'/>
   <note>
    The syntax is a same as for the noNamespaceSchemaLocation attribute 
    that may occur in an instance document: e.g."file_name.xsd". The 
    user may specify only one XML Schema. For more information see the
    documentation for the 
    http://apache.org/xml/properties/schema/external-schemaLocation 
    property.
   </note>
  </property>
  <property name='http://apache.org/xml/properties/input-buffer-size'
            id='input-buffer-size'>
   <desc>
    The size of the input buffer in the readers. This determines how many
    bytes to read for each chunk.
   </desc>
   <type>java.lang.Integer</type>
   <access general='read-write'/>
   <note>
    Some tests indicate that a bigger buffer size can improve the parsing
    performance for relatively large files. The default buffer size
    in Xerces is 2K. This would give a good performance for small documents
    (less than 10K). For documents larger than 10K, specifying the buffer
    size to 4K or 8K will significantly improve the performance. But it's not
    recommended to set it to a value larger than 16K. For really tiny
    documents (1K, for example), you can also set it to a value less than 2K,
    to get the best performance.
   </note>
  </property>
  
  <property name='http://apache.org/xml/properties/entity-expansion-limit'
            id='entity-expansion-limit'>
   <desc>
      Application can set the limit of number of entities that should be expanded by the parser.
	When this property is set by the application, before opening any new entity parser checks for
	the entity expansion limit set by the application, if number of entities expanded exceeds the
	entity expansion limit, parser throws fatal error.
   </desc>
   <type>java.lang.Integer</type>
   <access general='read-write'/>
   <note>
      Default value for this property would be 'null' It means there would not be any limit for number
	of entities that can be expanded by the parser.
   </note>
  </property>
  
  
 </pcategory>
 <pcategory name='DOM Properties'>
  <property name='http://apache.org/xml/properties/dom/current-element-node'
            id='dom.current-element-node'>
   <desc>The current DOM element node while parsing.</desc>
   <type>org.w3c.dom.Element</type>
   <access general='read-only'/>
   <note>
    This property is useful for determining the location with a DOM
    document when an error occurs.
   </note>
  </property>
  <property name='http://apache.org/xml/properties/dom/document-class-name'
            id='dom.document-class-name'>
   <desc>
    The fully qualified name of the class implementing 
    the <code>org.w3c.dom.Document</code> interface. The
    implementation used must have a zero argument constructor.  
   </desc>
   <type>java.lang.String</type>
   <default value='"org.apache.xerces.dom.DocumentImpl"'/>
   <access general='read-write'/>
   <note>
    When the document class name is set to a value other than the 
    name of the default document factory, the deferred node expansion 
    feature does not work.   
   </note>
  </property>
 </pcategory>
 <pcategory name='SAX Properties'>
  <property name='http://xml.org/sax/properties/declaration-handler'
            id='declaration-handler'>
   <desc>Set the handler for DTD declarations.</desc>
   <type>org.xml.sax.ext.DeclHandler</type>
   <access general='read-write'/>
  </property>
  <property name='http://xml.org/sax/properties/lexical-handler'
            id='lexical-handler'>
   <desc>Set the handler for lexical parsing events.</desc>
   <type>org.xml.sax.ext.LexicalHandler</type>
   <access general='read-write'/>
  </property>
  <property name='http://xml.org/sax/properties/dom-node'
            id='dom-node'>
   <desc>
    The DOM node currently being visited, if SAX is being used as
    a DOM iterator. If the parser recognizes and supports this 
    property but is not currently visiting a DOM node, it should 
    return null.  
   </desc>
   <type>org.w3c.dom.Node</type>
   <access parsing='read-only' not-parsing='read-write'/>
   <note>
    This property is only for SAX parser implementations used as
    DOM tree walkers. Currently, Xerces does not have this
    functionality.
   </note>
  </property>
 </pcategory>
</properties>
