<?xml version="1.0" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE s1 SYSTEM "sbk:/style/dtd/document.dtd">

<s1 title="&javaparsername;">
	<s2 title="&javaparsername; &javaparserversion; Release">
		<p>The &javaparsername; &javaparserversion; release contains advanced
		parser functionality, such as XML Schema, DOM Level 2, and SAX version 2,
		in addition to supporting the industry-standard DOM Level 1 and SAX version 1
		APIs.</p>
        <p>
<!--
		&javaparsername; &javaparserversion; is the first in a series of ongoing updates -
		Watch <jump href="http://xml.apache.org">xml.apache.org</jump> 
		for new updates.  -->
        Note that because some of the standards, notably
		XML Schema, are still not complete, the stable API will definitely be 
		different from its current form in &javaparsername; &javaparserversion;. This is your chance to give us 
		feedback on the features that are important to you, and let us know
		whether the APIs that we are providing are the right ones. Please 
		direct your feedback to the &javaparsername; mailing list.</p>

	</s2>
	<s2 title="License Information">
		<p>The &javaparsername; &javaparserversion; release is available in both source code
			and precompiled binary (JAR files) form. &javaparsername;
			&javaparserversion; is licensed under the terms of Version
			1.1 of the  <jump href="http://xml.apache.org/dist/License.txt">Apache Software License</jump></p>
	</s2>
	<s2 title="Applications of the &javaparsername; Parser">
		<p>The rich generating and validating capabilities allow the &javaparsername; 
		Parser to be used for: </p>
		<ul>
			<li>Building XML-savvy Web servers </li>
			<li>The next generation of vertical applications which will use 
				XML as their data format. </li>
			<li>On-the-fly validation for creating XML editors </li>
			<li>Ensuring the integrity of e-business data expressed in XML </li>
			<li>Building truly internationalized XML applications. </li>
		</ul>
	</s2>
	<s2 title="XML Schema (alpha) Support">
		<p>This release includes preliminary support for the W3C XML Schema 
		Language. The <link idref="schema">Schema</link> page contains a 
		complete description of the 
		schema capabilities of this release. We intend to track the W3C XML 
		Schema Language in subsequent updates of &javaparsername;.</p>
	</s2>
	<s2 title="DOM Level 2 (alpha) Support">
		<p>This release include support for the 
		<jump href="http://www.w3.org/TR/WD-DOM-Level-2">DOM Level 2 Core</jump> and 
		<jump href="http://www.w3.org/TR/WD-DOM-Level-2">DOM Level 2 Traversal</jump> APIs. 
		We will be expanding our DOM Level 2 support to include all of DOM Level 2. At the moment, the DOM 
		Level 2 Traversal API's live in the org.apache.xerces.dom.domx.traversal 
		package.</p>
	</s2>
	<s2 title="SAX 2 (alpha) Support">
		<p>This release includes support for the <jump href="http://www.megginson.com/SAX/SAX2/">
		SAX Version 2</jump> API's which are being discussed on the 
		<jump href="http://www.lists.ic.ac.uk/hypermail/xml-dev/">XML-DEV</jump> mailing list. 
		These API's are still 
		under development, so they are subject to change in the future.</p>
	</s2>
	<s2 title="Configuration Mechanism">
		<p>&javaparsername; &javaparserversion; uses a collection of methods to configure 
		various settings in the parser. This release includes a new mechanism 
		for setting parser switches. This mechanism uses the SAX2 Configurable 
		interface. We have defined a series of properties and features for the 
		options available in &javaparsername;. The list of features can be found 
		<link idref="features">here</link>.</p>
	</s2>
</s1>
