<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- $Id$ -->
<!DOCTYPE releases SYSTEM 'dtd/releases.dtd'>
<releases>
 <release version='NOT YET RELEASED'>
  <desc>
  </desc>
  <changes>
   <update>
    <note> Added an interface, XMLResourceIdentifier, for
        describing the physical location of XML resources (external
        entities, schemas etc.) for use in grammar caching and entity
        resolution.  Updated XMLEntityResolver, XMLLocator,
        XMLDocumentHandler, XMLDocumentFragmentHandler, and
        XMLDTDHandler to use this new interface instead of unwieldy
        lists of Strings in various callbacks.
    </note>
    <submitter name="Neil Graham"/>
   </update>
   <add>
        <note> Added interfaces to support grammar caching
        facilities in the
        <code>org.apache.xerces.xni.grammars</code> package.
        </note>
    <submitter name="Neil Graham"/>
    </add>
   <update>
    <note>
     Updated Xerces Native Interface to add augmentations to
     document fragment handler, DTD handler, and the DTD content
     model handler interfaces. Additional methods were also 
     renamed and/or modified.
    </note>
    <submitter name='Andy Clark'/>
   </update>
   <add>
    <note>
     Added ability to override default parser configuration.
    </note>
    <submitter name='Andy Clark'/>
   </add>
   <fix>
        <note> Fixed a bug in the ui.DOMParserSaveEncoding sample.
        </note>
        <submitter name="Joerg Vogel, Neil Graham"/>
   </fix>
   <add>
    <note>Implemented support for UCS-4 and UCS-2 encodings.</note>
    <submitter name='Neil Graham'/>
   </add>
   <add>
    <note>Added internal subset string to DOM.</note>
    <submitter name='Andy Clark'/>
   </add>
  </changes>
 </release>
 <release version='Xerces 2.0.0 (beta4)'>
  <desc>
   This release fixes a number of bugs, introduces more changes to the Xerces
   Native Interface, provides partial experimental DOM Level 3 implementation,
   and includes full XML Schema support.
  </desc>
  <changes>
    <add>
        <note> 
            Implemented schema particle derivation restriction checking
        </note>
        <submitter name="Lisa Martin"/>
    </add>
    <add>
        <note> 
            Added checking for schema constraint cos-element-consistent 
        </note>
        <submitter name="Lisa Martin"/>
    </add>
    <fix>
        <note> 
            resolved misc. SAX2 bugs
        </note>
        <submitter name="Lisa Martin"/>
    </fix>
    <add>
    <note>
     Added implementation of DOMInputSource, DOMError, DOMLocator and wrappers
     for entity resolver and error handler (DOM Level 3).
    </note>
    <submitter name='Gopal Sharma, Elena Litani'/>
   </add>

   <add>
    <note>
     Added implementation of DOMWriter, DocumentLS, DOMImplementationLS and new
     features support for save and load: create-cdata-nodes,
     split-cdata-sections (DOM Level 3).
    </note>
    <submitter name='Rahul Srivastava, Elena Litani'/>
   </add>

   <add>
    <note>
     Added implementation of DOMBuilder, DOMASBuilder and partial
     implementation of ASModel.  Add support for a new feature
     "include-comments" (DOM Level 3).
    </note>
    <submitter name='Pavani Mukthipudi, Neil Graham, Elena Litani'/>
   </add>

   <add>
    <note>
     Added Augmentations interface to core XNI interfaces and PSVI interfaces
     as an extension to XNI (unstable). Added DOM Level 3 interfaces to
     xerces.dom3 package. Modified samples accordingly.
    </note>
    <submitter name='Elena Litani'/>
   </add>

   <add>
    <note>
        Implemented split of xerces.jar file into an API-only jar file
        (xmlParserAPIs.jar) and a jarfile containing only the API
        implementation (xercesImpl.jar).
     </note>
     <submitter name="Neil Graham"/>
    </add>

   <update>
    <note>
     Modified XNI document handler interface to include Augmentations as an
     extra parameter on each parser event. Modified XMLAttributes interface to
     include getter methods for augmentations.
    </note>
    <submitter name='Elena Litani'/>
   </update>

   <add>
    <note>
     Implemented PSVI support in Xerces and added PSVIWriter, PSVIParser and
     PSVIConfiguration sample files.
    </note>
    <submitter name='Arun Yadav, Elena Litani, Sandy Gao'/>
   </add>
   
   <add>
    <note>
     Added "external-schemaLocation" and "external-noNamespaceSchemaLocation"
     properties.
    </note>
    <submitter name='Sandy Gao'/>
   </add>

   <add>
    <note>
     New schema simple type interface and implementation. It fixes various bugs
     in the old implementation, and provides enough information for PSVI
     support.
    </note>
    <submitter name='Sandy Gao, Neeraj Bajaj'/>
   </add>

   <update>
    <note>
     Internalize all symbols in SymbolTable using
     java.lang.String#intern(). Now applications can compare the symbols by
     reference.
    </note>
    <submitter name='Sandy Gao'/>
   </update>

   <add>
    <note>
     Added "schema-full-checking" feature, and implemented "Unique Particle
     Attribution" constraint.
    </note>
    <submitter name='Sandy Gao'/>
   </add>

   <fix>
    <note>
     Changed the default configuration to standard parser configuration (that
     does not include XML Schema validator), modified how and when the pipeline
     is constructed.
    </note>
    <submitter name='Elena Litani'/>
   </fix>

   <fix>
    <note>
     Changed XML Schema validation behavior back to validate only if the
     http://xml.org/sax/features/validation feature is true. Note: XML Schema
     validation is off by default.
    </note>
    <submitter name='Andy Clark'/>
   </fix>

   <fix>
    <note>
     Added constructor to new DTDXSParserConfiguration so it can
     share settings from a parent configuration.
    </note>
    <submitter name='Andy Clark'/>
   </fix>
 
   <fix>
    <note>
     The parser no longer wraps RuntimeException with XNIException
     in the parse method.
    </note>
    <submitter name='Andy Clark'/>
   </fix>

   <fix>
    <note>
      Fixed cloneNode() for Entity, EntityReference and DocumentType. Fixed
      importNode() of EntityReference nodes which mistakenly carried the old
      value. Fixed handling EntityReference node subtrees that left the node
      empty in non deferred DOM.
    </note>
    <submitter name='Arnaud Le Hors'/>
   </fix>

   <fix>
    <note>
     Added missing default attribute values in the DOM and fixed 
     double entity value bug in deferred DOM.
    </note>
    <submitter name='Andy Clark'/>
   </fix>

   <fix>
    <note>
     Fixed getElementById() in the DOMParser. Bound namespace attributes to
     http://www.w3.org/2000/xmlns/ (DOM only).
    </note>
    <submitter name='Elena Litani'/>
   </fix>

    <fix>
    <note>Various documentation fixes.</note>
    <submitter name='Andy Clark, Elena Litani'/>
   </fix>
  
   <add>
    <note>
     Added more DOM Level 3 interfaces to xerces.dom3 package. Implemented
     DOMImplementationRegistry (DOMImplementationSource really),
     Node.set/getTextContent(), Node.isSameNode(), Node.getInterface(),
     Node.set/getUserData(). Extended dom.mem.Test to test these additions.
    </note>
    <submitter name='Arnaud Le Hors'/>
   </add>

   <add>
    <note>
        Added ASBuilder sample to the DOM samples package to show how
        to use the new DOM level 3 ASBuilder interface to implement a
        form of grammar caching.
    </note>
    <submitter name='Sandy Gao'/>
   </add>

   <fix>
    <note>
        Enabled the parser to process documents encoded in EBCDIC and
        UTF-16.
    </note>
    <submitter name='Neil Graham'/>
   </fix>
  </changes>
 </release>

 <release version='Xerces 2.0.0 (beta3)'>
  <desc>
   This release fixes a number of bugs, introduces some changes to
   the Xerces Native Interface, and is the first Xerces2 release to
   include XML Schema validation support. Please note that the XML
   Schema validation code was completely rewritten for Xerces2 and
   should be considered alpha at this time.
  </desc>
  <changes>
  
 <add>
    <note>
     Redesigned and rewrote XML Schema validation code. Also updated
     standard parser configuration to include the XML Schema validator 
     in the document pipeline by default.
    </note>
    <submitter name='Sandy Gao, Lisa Martin, Neil Graham, Elena Litani, Rahul Srivastava, Gopal Sharma, Pavani Mukthipudi, Neeraj Bajaj'/>
   </add>

  <add>
    <note>
     Added new default parser configuration that includes DTD and XML Schema
     validators (DTDXSParserConfiguration). Implemented dynamic validation for
     both validators.
    </note>
    <submitter name='Sandy Gao, Elena Litani'/>
   </add>
   
  <fix>
    <note>
     Synced up javax.xml.parsers package with latest code from xml-commons
  module and various bug fixes.
    </note>
    <submitter name='Edwin Goei'/>
   </fix> 
   <fix>
    <note>
    DOM/ DOMParser bug fixes. 
    </note>
    <submitter name='Ted Leung, Andy Clark, Elena Litani, Arun Yadav'/>
   </fix> 


   <fix>
    <note>
     Fixed newline normalization bug. Previously, the sequence #x0A #x0D
     was being converted to #x0A instead of #x0A #x0A per section 2.11 of
     the XML 1.0 specification. Thanks to Aleksander Slominski for the
     bug report.
    </note>
    <submitter name='Andy Clark'/>
   </fix>
   <update>
    <note>
     Added getter methods to XMLParserConfiguration interface and added
     filter interfaces for components that consume and produce document 
     and DTD information.
    </note>
    <submitter name='Andy Clark'/>
   </update>
   <fix>
    <note>
     Fixed DTD scanner from reporting entity boundaries appearing
     inside of markup declarations. Entity boundaries appearing
     in the content model of an element declaration is still
     reported, though.
    </note>
    <submitter name='Andy Clark'/>
   </fix>
   <update>
    <note>
     Simplified XMLAttributes interface by removing the methods
     related to entities appearing in attribute values.
    </note>
    <submitter name='Andy Clark'/>
   </update>
   <update>
    <note>
     Changed the XMLDTDHandler defined in XNI to add a non-normalized 
     value parameter to the internal element declaration callback. Also
     implemented the non-normalized value for attribute values.
    </note>
    <submitter name='Andy Clark'/>
   </update>
   <fix>
    <note>
     Fixed bug in entity manager that would never resolve IANA encoding
     names to Java encoding names properly. (Bug #3449) 
    </note>
    <submitter name='Pavani Mukthipudi' mailto='Pavani.Mukthipudi@sun.com'/>
   </fix>
   <fix>
    <note>
     Fixed bug in SAX parser that was not forwarding external entity
     declarations in the DTD. (Bug #3392)
    </note>
    <submitter name='Neeraj Bajaj' mailto='Neeraj.Bajaj@sun.com'/>
   </fix>
   <add>
    <note>
     Separated the XMLDocumentScannerImpl class so that it derives
     from XMLDocumentFragmentScannerImpl which enables an
     application to parse document fragments.
    </note>
    <submitter name='Andy Clark'/>
   </add>
   <add>
    <note>
     Ported the deferred DOM implementation from the Xerces 1.x
     codebase.
    </note>
    <submitter name='Arnaud  Le Hors'/>
   </add>
  </changes>
 </release>
 <release version='&ParserName; 2.0.0 (beta2)'>
  <desc>
   This is primarily a bug fix release. However, a new XNI
   interface and additional documentation have been added.
  </desc>
  <changes>
   <fix>
    <note>
     Fixed bug for when namespace bindings were added as default
     attributes from the DTD.
    </note>
    <submitter name='Andy Clark'/>
   </fix>
   <fix>
    <note>
     Fixed Xerces2 standard components to properly recognize and use
     the features and properties that they are documented to accept.
    </note>
    <submitter name='Andy Clark'/>
   </fix>
   <add>
    <note>
     Added documentation to the XNI Manual for re-using the Xerces2
     parser components.
    </note>
    <submitter name='Andy Clark'/>
   </add>
   <update>
    <note>
     Moved Xerces 1.x to "xerces_j_1" branch and moved Xerces2 to the main 
     trunk of the "xml-xerces" module.
    </note>
    <submitter name='Arnaud  Le Hors'/>
   </update>
   <fix>
    <note>
     Improved ability of document and DTD scanners to perform pull parsing.
    </note>
    <submitter name='Andy Clark'/>
   </fix>
   <fix>
    <note>
     Fixed bug where namespace binder would turn an emptyElement callback into
     startElement and endElement callbacks.
    </note>
    <submitter name='Andy Clark'/>
   </fix>
   <update>
    <note>
     Updated standard parser configuration to separate DTD validation
     and namespace binding in the parsing pipeline.
    </note>
    <submitter name='Andy Clark'/>
   </update>
   <remove>
    <note>
     Removed old XML Schema code that was not being used. This code 
     is intended to be replaced by either a port of the Xerces 1.x 
     XML Schema implementation or by a re-designed, re-implemented
     XML Schema implementation.
    </note>
    <submitter name='Andy Clark'/>
   </remove>
   <fix>
    <note>
     Fixed bug in scanner that allowed the built-in entity references
     to be sent via XNI. The default value for this feature should have
     been false.
    </note>
    <submitter name='Andy Clark'/>
   </fix>
   <fix>
    <note>Fixed several SAX bugs.</note>
    <submitter name='Andy Clark'/>
   </fix>
   <update>
    <note>
     Synchronized DOM implementation code from Xerces 1.x codebase.
    </note>
    <submitter name='Andy Clark'/>
   </update>
  </changes>
 </release>
 <release version='&ParserName; 2.0.0 (beta)'>
  <desc>
   First beta release of the Xerces2 code. Besides numerous bug 
   fixes, this release has changes and additions to XNI. The new
   XNI parser configuration framework has been added in this release.
   Refer to the <link idref='xni'>XNI Manual</link> for complete
   information.
  </desc>
  <changes>
   <add>
    <note>
     Added document and DTD scanner interfaces to XNI to allow
     parser configuration pipelines to be constructed generically.
    </note>
    <submitter name='Andy Clark'/>
   </add>
   <fix>
    <note>
     Fixed bug in DTD grammar for mixed content models that was 
     building the wrong validation content model.
    </note>
    <submitter name='Sandy Gao'/>
   </fix>
   <update>
    <note>
     Removed SAX dependency from XNI framework. Now the only
     dependence on external API such as SAX is in the implementation
     of the AbstractSAXParser and DOMParser so that legacy code
     doesn't break.
    </note>
    <submitter name='Andy Clark'/>
   </update>
   <update>
    <note>
     Rewrote existing documentation, added XNI information, cleaned
     up stylesheets, and converted some docs to use custom DTDs.
    </note>
    <submitter name='Andy Clark'/>
   </update>
   <fix>
    <note>DTD method ordering problem for INCLUDE/IGNORE sections.</note>
    <submitter name='Petr Kuzel'/>
   </fix>
   <update>
    <note>Improved DFA build-time performance.</note>
    <submitter name='ATOZAWA@jp.ibm.com' mailto='ATOZAWA@jp.ibm.com'/>
   </update>
   <update>
    <note>Synchronized with Xerces 1.3.0</note>
    <submitter name='Arnaud  Le Hors'/>
   </update>
  </changes>
 </release>
 <release version='&ParserName; 2.0.0 (alpha)'>
  <desc>Initial alpha release of Xerces2 code.</desc>
 </release>
</releases>
