<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- $Id$ -->
<!DOCTYPE releases SYSTEM 'dtd/releases.dtd'>
<releases>
  <release version="TBD">
    <desc>
      This release fixes a number of bugs, and adds some functionality.
    </desc>
    <changes>
      <add>
	<note>Schema Component API interfaces and implementation; full PSVI support.
	</note>
	<submitter name='Sandy Gao, Elena Litani'/>
      </add>

      <update>
	<note>
	  Add XMLResourceIdentifier to startExternalSubset() method defined in 
	  XNI XMLDTDHandler. 
	  That allows supporting baseURI for an external subset.
	</note>
	<submitter name='Elena Litani'/>
      </update>
      <add>
	<note>
	   Add implementation for baseURI, documentURI, normalizeDocument 
           and required normalize document features. Added support for DOM revalidation 
           against XML Schemas. [DOM Level 3]
	</note>
	<submitter name='Elena Litani'/>
      </add>
      <add>
        <note>
          Reorganized the code in Xerces DOM implementation to expose DOM Level 3
          functionality via org.w3c.dom package.
          Added several build targets for building customized xerces jar files that include
          DOM Level 3 Core and Load/Save interfaces and 
          implementation of those interfaces: jars-dom3, apijar-dom3, sampjar-dom3. 
       </note>
	<submitter name='Arnaud Le Hors, Elena Litani'/>
     </add>
      <update>
	<note>
	  Updated xni.DocumentTracer sample to print augmentations for events.
	  This makes it easier to debug configurations that augment the document's
	  infoset.
	</note>
	<submitter name='Andy Clark'/>
      </update>
      <update>
	<note>
	  Removed dependence on SAX attribute interfaces from XMLAttributesImpl
	  utility class. The AbstractSAXParser already defines a SAX attribute
	  proxy class so that the parser and components can be properly layered.
	</note>
	<submitter name='Andy Clark'/>
      </update>
      <update>
	<note>
	  Improved handling of settings in parser classes making it easier
	  to re-use the parsers with other parser configurations. Previously,
	  the parser instances assumed that all configurations supported
	  various settings (i.e. the parser would set default values without 
	  first adding the recognized features and property identifiers to
	  the parser configuration).
	</note>
	<submitter name='Andy Clark'/>
      </update>
      <fix>
	<note>
	  Fixed bug in HTML DOM implementation that was causing xerces.dom
	  element nodes to be created instead of the appropriate HTML element
	  nodes.
	</note>
	<submitter name='Andy Clark'/>
      </fix>
      <fix>
	<note>
	  Fixed bug to avoid null pointer exception in AbstractDOMParser when
	  locator information is not available from parser configuration.
	</note>
	<submitter name='Andy Clark'/>
      </fix>
      <fix>
	<note>
	  Fixed bug in WrappedInput/OutputStream classes reported by Morten Bjørhus.
	</note>
	<submitter name='Andy Clark'/>
      </fix>
      
      <fix>
	<note>The DTD validator failed to report 
	  "undeclared element" error if an attribute was 
	  declared for an undeclared element.</note>
	<submitter name='Elena Litani'/>
      </fix>
      <fix>
        <note>Performance fixes:  replaced code that increases array sizes by catching ArrayIndexOutOfBoundsExceptions
            with code that checks the sizes of the relevant arrays.  Also streamlined
            several method calls in the DTD Grammar classes to account for the 
            fact that scope is not relevant for this type of grammar.  Finally,
            improved algorithm for recognizing entities and notations.
        </note>
        <submitter name="Henry Zongaro, Neil Graham"/>
      </fix>
      <update>
	<note>
	  Compress jars by default.  We have not done so in the past,
	  and it will be useful to see if this proves problematic or
	  beneficial.
	</note>
	<submitter name="Neil Graham"/>
      </update>
      <add>
	<note>
	  Added several build targets for building customized xercesImpl
	  jarfiles.  Now we can build a DTD-only version, and a DTD-only
	  version also excluding support for the HTML/WML DOM.
	</note>
	<submitter name="Neil Graham"/>
      </add>
      <fix>
	<note>
	  Parser now reads external entities one chunk at a time, 
	  rather than a character at a time;
	  this increases performance dramatically in certain circumstances.  
	  This fix also allows a number of EBCDIC encodings to work which did
	  not work previously.  
	</note>
	<submitter name="Neil Graham, Henry Zongaro"/>
      </fix>

      <update>
	<note>Performance enhancement: implemented DOM node and 
	  declaration pools that reduce number of objects created 
	  during building of XML Schema grammars.
	</note>
	<submitter name='Elena Litani'/>
      </update>
      <update>
	<note>Improved performance for non-deferred DOM: reduced 
	  number of concatenations for characters (bug #5602)
	</note>
	<submitter name='Elena Litani'/>
      </update>

      <update>
	<note>According to the namespace spec errata, namespace declaration
          attributes should be bound to a special namespace; and errors should
          be reported on illegal bindings of "xmlns" and "xml" prefixes and
          their namespaces.
	</note>
	<submitter name='Sandy Gao'/>
      </update>

      <update>
	<note>Refined schema error messages: provide more descriptive error
          messages for simple type validation errors; avoid cascading errors
          when a grammar for a given namespace is not found, or when components
          from a certain namespace can't be accessed from a given schema
          document.
	</note>
	<submitter name='Sandy Gao'/>
      </update>

      <update>
	<note>Changed the lexical representation of gMonth from "--MM--" to "--MM".
	</note>
	<submitter name='Sandy Gao'/>
      </update>

      <fix>
	<note>Decimal point shouldn't be allowed in integer-derived types;
           "fractionDigits" and "totalDigits" should be calculated on the value space.
	</note>
	<submitter name='Sandy Gao'/>
      </fix>

      <fix>
	<note>Fixed several DOM bugs. Xerces now passes 
	  W3C DOM Level 1 Core test suite.
	</note>
	<submitter name='Elena Litani'/>
      </fix> 

      <update>
	<note>Improved management of ID attributes in the DOM so that
	  Document.getElementByID is more reliable.
	</note>
	<submitter name='Arnaud  Le Hors'/>
      </update>
      <fix>
	<note>Applied patch from Scott Sanders to fix Java serialization of the
	  DOM and add a test.
	</note>
	<submitter name='Arnaud  Le Hors'/>
      </fix>


      <fix>
	<note>Applied patch from Henry Zongaro to fix a ClassCastException 
	  in the deferred DOM.</note>
	<submitter name='Elena Litani'/>
      </fix>
      <fix>
	<note>Applied patch from Fabio Riccardi to reset normalize value 
	  in the PSVI.
	</note>
	<submitter name='Elena Litani'/>
      </fix>
      <fix>
	<note>Applied patch from Joe Kesselman that fixes 
	  NPE in a NodeIterator (bug #6888).
	</note>
	<submitter name='Elena Litani'/>
      </fix>



    </changes>
  </release>
  <release version='Xerces 2.0.1'>
    <desc>
      This release fixes a number of bugs.
    </desc>
    <changes>

      <fix>
	<note>
	  Fixed and closed bugs filed in Bugzilla.
	</note>
	<submitter name='Sandy Gao, Pavani Mukthipudi, Elena Litani, Rahul Srivastava, Neil Graham, Neeraj Bajaj, Lisa Martin, Gopal Sharma, Andy Clark, Arun Yadav'/>
      </fix>

      <add>
	<note>
	  Added the support of reporting line/column numbers of schema errors.
	</note>
	<submitter name='Sandy Gao'/>
      </add>

      <update>
	<note>
	  When creating DOM nodes, use Strings we already have, instead of
	  creating new ones.
	</note>
	<submitter name='Sandy Gao'/>
      </update>

      <update>
	<note>
	  Updated DTD datatypes to use the new datatype interfaces.
	</note>
	<submitter name='Sandy Gao'/>
      </update>

      <fix>
	<note>
	  Fixed an entity resolution bug: we passed null as the system ID
	  to the entity resolver.
	</note>
	<submitter name='Sandy Gao'/>
      </fix>

      <fix>
	<note>
	  Fixed a bug in the handling of URI's containing "../../".
	</note>
	<submitter name='Sandy Gao'/>
      </fix>

      <fix>
	<note>
	  Fixed a thread-safety bug in schema simple type implementation.
	  The implementation class should be stateless after construction.
	</note>
	<submitter name='Sandy Gao'/>
      </fix>

      <fix>
	<note>Fixed bugs in namespace algorithm for serialization.</note>
	<submitter name='Elena Litani'/>
      </fix>

      <fix>
	<note>Fixed a bug in deferred DOM for CDATA nodes.</note>
	<submitter name='Elena Litani'/>
      </fix>

      <fix>
	<note>Enabled processing of base 64-encoded material on OS/390.</note>
	<submitter name='Neil Graham, Steve Dulin'/>
      </fix>

      <update>
	<note>Modified XNI grammar interfaces such that Grammars now have 
	  an associated XMLGrammarDescription and XMLGrammarDescriptions record the
	  type of the grammar.  </note>
	<submitter name="Neil Graham"/>
      </update>

      <fix>
	<note>Fixed a bug related to Signature of call back attributeDecl in XNI samples.</note>
	<submitter name='Rahul Srivastava'/>
      </fix>

      <fix>
	<note>Fixed a bug related to feature prefix in AbstractDOMParser.</note>
	<submitter name='Rahul Srivastava'/>
      </fix>

      <add>
	<note>
	  Added the support for defer loading of schema gramars, grammar is parsed
	  only when there is reference to any schema component from that namespace.
	</note>
	<submitter name='Neeraj Bajaj'/>
      </add>

      <update>
	<note>
	  JAXP 1.2 schemaSource property, if the String given is relative URI, 
	  now it is resolved against the instance document being parsed.
	</note>
	<submitter name='Neeraj Bajaj'/>
      </update>

      <fix>
	<note>
	  Fixed a bug related to SchemaNormalizedValue to expose it only when
	  validation attempted is full.
	</note>
	<submitter name='Pavani Mukthipudi'/>
      </fix>

    </changes>
  </release>

  <release version='Xerces 2.0.0'>
    <desc>
      This is the first production-quality release of the Xerces2 Java
      XML parser.  We are confident that it also marks the stabilization
      of the XNI API, although changes in XNI are still possible.  As
      well as these XNI improvements and extensions, a host of bugs
      and limitations that existed in Xerces 2.0.0beta4 have been fixed in 
      this release.
    </desc>
    <changes>
      
      <add>
	<note>Implemented support for UCS-4 and UCS-2 encodings.</note>
	<submitter name='Neil Graham'/>
      </add>
      
      <add>
	<note>
	  Added ability to override default parser configuration.
	</note>
	<submitter name='Andy Clark'/>
      </add>

      <add>
	<note>Implemented DOM Level 3 isEqualNode() method
	</note>
	<submitter name='Arnaud Le Hors'/>
      </add>
      
      <add>
	<note>Implemented namespace fixup during serialization of DOM tree.</note>
	<submitter name='Elena Litani'/>
      </add>
      
      <add>
	<note>Added implementation for new Xerces features validation/schema/normalized-value and 
	  validation/schema/element-default</note>
	<submitter name='Elena Litani'/>
      </add>


      <add>
        <note>Implemented current-element-node property</note>
        <submitter name='Ted Leung'/>
      </add> 
      
      
      <add>
	<note>Added internal subset string to DOM.</note>
	<submitter name='Andy Clark'/>
      </add>

      <add>
	<note>Added support for warn-on-duplicate-attdef xerces feature
	  validation/warn-on-duplicate-attdef
	</note>
	<submitter name='Neeraj Bajaj'/>
      </add>

      
      <update>
	<note> Added an interface, XMLResourceIdentifier, for
	  describing the physical location of XML resources (external
	  entities, schemas etc.) for use in grammar caching and entity
	  resolution.  Updated XMLEntityResolver, XMLLocator,
	  XMLDocumentHandler, XMLDocumentFragmentHandler, and
	  XMLDTDHandler to use this new interface consistently instead of unwieldy
	  lists of Strings in various callbacks.
	</note>
	<submitter name="Neil Graham"/>
      </update>
      
      <update>
	<note>
	  Updated Xerces Native Interface to add augmentations to
	  document fragment handler, DTD handler, and the DTD content
	  model handler interfaces. Additional methods were also 
	  renamed and/or modified.
	</note>
	<submitter name='Andy Clark'/>
      </update>
      
      
      <update>
	<note>
	  Updated Xerces Native Interface to add methods to Augmentations, XMLAttributes, and
	  modify PSVI interfaces.
	</note>
	<submitter name='Elena Litani'/>
      </update>
      
      <update>
	<note>
	  Cleaned up separation between DOMParser and DeferredDOM by
	  moving part of the code from createDeferredElement back into the parser,
	  this has several benefits including to only have to walk the list of
	  attributes once
	</note>
	<submitter name='Arnaud Le Hors'/>
      </update>

      <update>
	<note>Provided support for fundamental facets in DV implementation  </note>
	<submitter name='Neeraj Bajaj, Sandy Gao'/>
      </update>
      

      <fix>
        <note> Moved schema simple type error messages to the property file to enable localization.
        </note>
        <submitter name="Sandy Gao"/>
      </fix>
      
      <fix>
        <note> Fixed various bugs related to the dependency between schema documents.
        </note>
        <submitter name="Sandy Gao"/>
      </fix>
      
      <fix>
        <note> Modified URI resolution strategy so that Windows network paths are recognized.
        </note>
        <submitter name="Sandy Gao"/>
      </fix>
      
      <fix>
        <note> Fixed various bugs related to schema components traversal and validation.
        </note>
        <submitter name="Sandy Gao"/>
      </fix>
      
      <fix>
        <note> Fixed a bug in the ui.DOMParserSaveEncoding sample.
        </note>
        <submitter name="Joerg Vogel, Neil Graham"/>
      </fix>
      
      <fix>
        <note> 
	  Modified XMLDTDScanner to synchronize start/end entity calls.
	  Fixed XMLDocumentScannerImpl so it always checks settings for load-external-dtd feature. 
	  Modified implementation of setDocumentHandler(): now user can change document handler
	  during the parse.
        </note>
        <submitter name="Elena Litani"/>
      </fix>
      
      <fix>
        <note> 
	  Fixed DOM L2 bugs: synchronization for entity reference nodes, 
	  cloning of attribute node, report of event phases.             
        </note>
        <submitter name="Arnaud Le Hors, Elena Litani"/>
      </fix>

      <fix>
        <note> 
	  Fixed a bug in XMLDocumentFragmentScannerImpl occuring when a ] is encountered          at the end of an entity.                        
        </note>
        <submitter name="Arnaud Le Hors"/>
      </fix> 
      
      <fix>
        <note>Fixed misc. SAX bugs.
        </note>
        <submitter name="Lisa Martin"/>
      </fix>

      <fix>
        <note>Fixed JAXP implementation of schemaLanguage property.
        </note>
        <submitter name="Edwin Goei"/>
      </fix>

      
      <fix>
        <note>Massive Javadoc fixes. 
        </note>
        <submitter name="Ted Leung, Neeraj Bajaj, Rahul Srivastava"/>
      </fix>

      <fix>
        <note>Fixed external-schemaLocation and external-noNamespaceSchemalocation 
	  properties related bug (# 5768)        
        </note>
        <submitter name="Gopal Sharma"/>
      </fix>


      <fix>
        <note>Fixed namespaces and namespace-prefixes related SAX bug.
        </note>
        <submitter name="Rahul Srivastava"/>
      </fix>

      <fix>
        <note>Corrected features documentation for string-interning feature.
        </note>
        <submitter name="Rahul Srivastava"/>
      </fix>
      
      <fix>
        <note>Fixed the bug in which duplicate attribute definitions were not ignored
          and error was reported for ID datatype and Notation.
        </note>
        <submitter name="Neeraj Bajaj"/>
      </fix>

      <fix>
        <note>Fixed the bug where 'locale' value was not set for StandardParserConfiguration.
        </note>
        <submitter name="Takuki Kamiya, Neeraj Bajaj"/>
      </fix>

    </changes>
  </release>
  

  <release version='Xerces 2.0.0 (beta4)'>
    <desc>
      This release fixes a number of bugs, introduces more changes to the Xerces
      Native Interface, provides partial experimental DOM Level 3 implementation,
      and includes full XML Schema support.
    </desc>
    <changes>
      <add>
        <note> 
	  Implemented schema particle derivation restriction checking
        </note>
        <submitter name="Lisa Martin"/>
      </add>
      <add>
        <note> 
	  Added checking for schema constraint cos-element-consistent 
        </note>
        <submitter name="Lisa Martin"/>
      </add>
      <fix>
        <note> 
	  resolved misc. SAX2 bugs
        </note>
        <submitter name="Lisa Martin"/>
      </fix>
      <add>
	<note>
	  Added implementation of DOMInputSource, DOMError, DOMLocator and wrappers
	  for entity resolver and error handler (DOM Level 3).
	</note>
	<submitter name='Gopal Sharma, Elena Litani'/>
      </add>

      <add>
	<note>
	  Added implementation of DOMWriter, DocumentLS, DOMImplementationLS and new
	  features support for save and load: create-cdata-nodes,
	  split-cdata-sections (DOM Level 3).
	</note>
	<submitter name='Rahul Srivastava, Elena Litani'/>
      </add>

      <add>
	<note>
	  Added implementation of DOMBuilder, DOMASBuilder and partial
	  implementation of ASModel.  Add support for a new feature
	  "include-comments" (DOM Level 3).
	</note>
	<submitter name='Pavani Mukthipudi, Neil Graham, Elena Litani'/>
      </add>

      <add>
	<note>
	  Added Augmentations interface to core XNI interfaces and PSVI interfaces
	  as an extension to XNI (unstable). Added DOM Level 3 interfaces to
	  xerces.dom3 package. Modified samples accordingly.
	</note>
	<submitter name='Elena Litani'/>
      </add>

      <add>
	<note>
	  Implemented split of xerces.jar file into an API-only jar file
	  (xmlParserAPIs.jar) and a jarfile containing only the API
	  implementation (xercesImpl.jar).
	</note>
	<submitter name="Neil Graham"/>
      </add>

      <update>
	<note>
	  Modified XNI document handler interface to include Augmentations as an
	  extra parameter on each parser event. Modified XMLAttributes interface to
	  include getter methods for augmentations.
	</note>
	<submitter name='Elena Litani'/>
      </update>

      <add>
	<note>
	  Implemented PSVI support in Xerces and added PSVIWriter, PSVIParser and
	  PSVIConfiguration sample files.
	</note>
	<submitter name='Arun Yadav, Elena Litani, Sandy Gao'/>
      </add>
      
      <add>
	<note>
	  Added "external-schemaLocation" and "external-noNamespaceSchemaLocation"
	  properties.
	</note>
	<submitter name='Sandy Gao'/>
      </add>

      <add>
	<note>
	  New schema simple type interface and implementation. It fixes various bugs
	  in the old implementation, and provides enough information for PSVI
	  support.
	</note>
	<submitter name='Sandy Gao, Neeraj Bajaj'/>
      </add>

      <update>
	<note>
	  Internalize all symbols in SymbolTable using
	  java.lang.String#intern(). Now applications can compare the symbols by
	  reference.
	</note>
	<submitter name='Sandy Gao'/>
      </update>

      <add>
	<note>
	  Added "schema-full-checking" feature, and implemented "Unique Particle
	  Attribution" constraint.
	</note>
	<submitter name='Sandy Gao'/>
      </add>

      <fix>
	<note>
	  Changed the default configuration to standard parser configuration (that
	  does not include XML Schema validator), modified how and when the pipeline
	  is constructed.
	</note>
	<submitter name='Elena Litani'/>
      </fix>

      <fix>
	<note>
	  Changed XML Schema validation behavior back to validate only if the
	  http://xml.org/sax/features/validation feature is true. Note: XML Schema
	  validation is off by default.
	</note>
	<submitter name='Andy Clark'/>
      </fix>

      <fix>
	<note>
	  Added constructor to new DTDXSParserConfiguration so it can
	  share settings from a parent configuration.
	</note>
	<submitter name='Andy Clark'/>
      </fix>
      
      <fix>
	<note>
	  The parser no longer wraps RuntimeException with XNIException
	  in the parse method.
	</note>
	<submitter name='Andy Clark'/>
      </fix>

      <fix>
	<note>
	  Fixed cloneNode() for Entity, EntityReference and DocumentType. Fixed
	  importNode() of EntityReference nodes which mistakenly carried the old
	  value. Fixed handling EntityReference node subtrees that left the node
	  empty in non deferred DOM.
	</note>
	<submitter name='Arnaud Le Hors'/>
      </fix>

      <fix>
	<note>
	  Added missing default attribute values in the DOM and fixed 
	  double entity value bug in deferred DOM.
	</note>
	<submitter name='Andy Clark'/>
      </fix>

      <fix>
	<note>
	  Fixed getElementById() in the DOMParser. Bound namespace attributes to
	  http://www.w3.org/2000/xmlns/ (DOM only).
	</note>
	<submitter name='Elena Litani'/>
      </fix>

      <fix>
	<note>Various documentation fixes.</note>
	<submitter name='Andy Clark, Elena Litani'/>
      </fix>
      
      <add>
	<note>
	  Added more DOM Level 3 interfaces to xerces.dom3 package. Implemented
	  DOMImplementationRegistry (DOMImplementationSource really),
	  Node.set/getTextContent(), Node.isSameNode(), Node.getInterface(),
	  Node.set/getUserData(). Extended dom.mem.Test to test these additions.
	</note>
	<submitter name='Arnaud Le Hors'/>
      </add>

      <add>
	<note>
	  Added ASBuilder sample to the DOM samples package to show how
	  to use the new DOM level 3 ASBuilder interface to implement a
	  form of grammar caching.
	</note>
	<submitter name='Sandy Gao'/>
      </add>

      <fix>
	<note>
	  Enabled the parser to process documents encoded in EBCDIC and
	  UTF-16.
	</note>
	<submitter name='Neil Graham'/>
      </fix>
    </changes>
  </release>

  <release version='Xerces 2.0.0 (beta3)'>
    <desc>
      This release fixes a number of bugs, introduces some changes to
      the Xerces Native Interface, and is the first Xerces2 release to
      include XML Schema validation support. Please note that the XML
      Schema validation code was completely rewritten for Xerces2 and
      should be considered alpha at this time.
    </desc>
    <changes>
      
      <add>
	<note>
	  Redesigned and rewrote XML Schema validation code. Also updated
	  standard parser configuration to include the XML Schema validator 
	  in the document pipeline by default.
	</note>
	<submitter name='Sandy Gao, Lisa Martin, Neil Graham, Elena Litani, Rahul Srivastava, Gopal Sharma, Pavani Mukthipudi, Neeraj Bajaj'/>
      </add>

      <add>
	<note>
	  Added new default parser configuration that includes DTD and XML Schema
	  validators (DTDXSParserConfiguration). Implemented dynamic validation for
	  both validators.
	</note>
	<submitter name='Sandy Gao, Elena Litani'/>
      </add>
      
      <fix>
	<note>
	  Synced up javax.xml.parsers package with latest code from xml-commons
	  module and various bug fixes.
	</note>
	<submitter name='Edwin Goei'/>
      </fix> 
      <fix>
	<note>
	  DOM/ DOMParser bug fixes. 
	</note>
	<submitter name='Ted Leung, Andy Clark, Elena Litani, Arun Yadav'/>
      </fix> 


      <fix>
	<note>
	  Fixed newline normalization bug. Previously, the sequence #x0A #x0D
	  was being converted to #x0A instead of #x0A #x0A per section 2.11 of
	  the XML 1.0 specification. Thanks to Aleksander Slominski for the
	  bug report.
	</note>
	<submitter name='Andy Clark'/>
      </fix>
      <update>
	<note>
	  Added getter methods to XMLParserConfiguration interface and added
	  filter interfaces for components that consume and produce document 
	  and DTD information.
	</note>
	<submitter name='Andy Clark'/>
      </update>
      <fix>
	<note>
	  Fixed DTD scanner from reporting entity boundaries appearing
	  inside of markup declarations. Entity boundaries appearing
	  in the content model of an element declaration is still
	  reported, though.
	</note>
	<submitter name='Andy Clark'/>
      </fix>
      <update>
	<note>
	  Simplified XMLAttributes interface by removing the methods
	  related to entities appearing in attribute values.
	</note>
	<submitter name='Andy Clark'/>
      </update>
      <update>
	<note>
	  Changed the XMLDTDHandler defined in XNI to add a non-normalized 
	  value parameter to the internal element declaration callback. Also
	  implemented the non-normalized value for attribute values.
	</note>
	<submitter name='Andy Clark'/>
      </update>
      <fix>
	<note>
	  Fixed bug in entity manager that would never resolve IANA encoding
	  names to Java encoding names properly. (Bug #3449) 
	</note>
	<submitter name='Pavani Mukthipudi' mailto='Pavani.Mukthipudi@sun.com'/>
      </fix>
      <fix>
	<note>
	  Fixed bug in SAX parser that was not forwarding external entity
	  declarations in the DTD. (Bug #3392)
	</note>
	<submitter name='Neeraj Bajaj' mailto='Neeraj.Bajaj@sun.com'/>
      </fix>
      <add>
	<note>
	  Separated the XMLDocumentScannerImpl class so that it derives
	  from XMLDocumentFragmentScannerImpl which enables an
	  application to parse document fragments.
	</note>
	<submitter name='Andy Clark'/>
      </add>
      <add>
	<note>
	  Ported the deferred DOM implementation from the Xerces 1.x
	  codebase.
	</note>
	<submitter name='Arnaud  Le Hors'/>
      </add>
    </changes>
  </release>
  <release version='&ParserName; 2.0.0 (beta2)'>
    <desc>
      This is primarily a bug fix release. However, a new XNI
      interface and additional documentation have been added.
    </desc>
    <changes>
      <fix>
	<note>
	  Fixed bug for when namespace bindings were added as default
	  attributes from the DTD.
	</note>
	<submitter name='Andy Clark'/>
      </fix>
      <fix>
	<note>
	  Fixed Xerces2 standard components to properly recognize and use
	  the features and properties that they are documented to accept.
	</note>
	<submitter name='Andy Clark'/>
      </fix>
      <add>
	<note>
	  Added documentation to the XNI Manual for re-using the Xerces2
	  parser components.
	</note>
	<submitter name='Andy Clark'/>
      </add>
      <update>
	<note>
	  Moved Xerces 1.x to "xerces_j_1" branch and moved Xerces2 to the main 
	  trunk of the "xml-xerces" module.
	</note>
	<submitter name='Arnaud  Le Hors'/>
      </update>
      <fix>
	<note>
	  Improved ability of document and DTD scanners to perform pull parsing.
	</note>
	<submitter name='Andy Clark'/>
      </fix>
      <fix>
	<note>
	  Fixed bug where namespace binder would turn an emptyElement callback into
	  startElement and endElement callbacks.
	</note>
	<submitter name='Andy Clark'/>
      </fix>
      <update>
	<note>
	  Updated standard parser configuration to separate DTD validation
	  and namespace binding in the parsing pipeline.
	</note>
	<submitter name='Andy Clark'/>
      </update>
      <remove>
	<note>
	  Removed old XML Schema code that was not being used. This code 
	  is intended to be replaced by either a port of the Xerces 1.x 
	  XML Schema implementation or by a re-designed, re-implemented
	  XML Schema implementation.
	</note>
	<submitter name='Andy Clark'/>
      </remove>
      <fix>
	<note>
	  Fixed bug in scanner that allowed the built-in entity references
	  to be sent via XNI. The default value for this feature should have
	  been false.
	</note>
	<submitter name='Andy Clark'/>
      </fix>
      <fix>
	<note>Fixed several SAX bugs.</note>
	<submitter name='Andy Clark'/>
      </fix>
      <update>
	<note>
	  Synchronized DOM implementation code from Xerces 1.x codebase.
	</note>
	<submitter name='Andy Clark'/>
      </update>
    </changes>
  </release>
  <release version='&ParserName; 2.0.0 (beta)'>
    <desc>
      First beta release of the Xerces2 code. Besides numerous bug 
      fixes, this release has changes and additions to XNI. The new
      XNI parser configuration framework has been added in this release.
      Refer to the <link idref='xni'>XNI Manual</link> for complete
      information.
    </desc>
    <changes>
      <add>
	<note>
	  Added document and DTD scanner interfaces to XNI to allow
	  parser configuration pipelines to be constructed generically.
	</note>
	<submitter name='Andy Clark'/>
      </add>
      <fix>
	<note>
	  Fixed bug in DTD grammar for mixed content models that was 
	  building the wrong validation content model.
	</note>
	<submitter name='Sandy Gao'/>
      </fix>
      <update>
	<note>
	  Removed SAX dependency from XNI framework. Now the only
	  dependence on external API such as SAX is in the implementation
	  of the AbstractSAXParser and DOMParser so that legacy code
	  doesn't break.
	</note>
	<submitter name='Andy Clark'/>
      </update>
      <update>
	<note>
	  Rewrote existing documentation, added XNI information, cleaned
	  up stylesheets, and converted some docs to use custom DTDs.
	</note>
	<submitter name='Andy Clark'/>
      </update>
      <fix>
	<note>DTD method ordering problem for INCLUDE/IGNORE sections.</note>
	<submitter name='Petr Kuzel'/>
      </fix>
      <update>
	<note>Improved DFA build-time performance.</note>
	<submitter name='ATOZAWA@jp.ibm.com' mailto='ATOZAWA@jp.ibm.com'/>
      </update>
      <update>
	<note>Synchronized with Xerces 1.3.0</note>
	<submitter name='Arnaud  Le Hors'/>
      </update>
    </changes>
  </release>
  <release version='&ParserName; 2.0.0 (alpha)'>
    <desc>Initial alpha release of Xerces2 code.</desc>
  </release>
</releases>
