<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE releases SYSTEM 'dtd/releases.dtd'>
<releases>
 <release version='NOT YET RELEASED'>
  <desc>
   This is primarily a bug fix release with some minor changes to
   XNI interfaces related to DTD information.
  </desc>
  <changes>
   <update>
    <note>Added getter methods to XMLParserConfiguration interface.</note>
    <submitter name='Andy Clark'/>
   </update>
   <fix>
    <note>
     Fixed DTD scanner from reporting entity boundaries appearing
     inside of markup declarations. Entity boundaries appearing
     in the content model of an element declaration is still
     reported, though.
    </note>
    <submitter name='Andy Clark'/>
   </fix>
   <update>
    <note>
     Simplified XMLAttributes interface by removing the methods
     related to entities appearing in attribute values.
    </note>
    <submitter name='Andy Clark'/>
   </update>
   <update>
    <note>
     Changed the XMLDTDHandler defined in XNI to add a non-normalized 
     value parameter to the internal element declaration callback. Also
     implemented the non-normalized value for attribute values.
    </note>
    <submitter name='Andy Clark'/>
   </update>
   <fix>
    <note>
     Fixed bug in entity manager that would never resolve IANA encoding
     names to Java encoding names properly. (Bug #3449) 
    </note>
    <submitter name='Pavani Mukthipudi' email='Pavani.Mukthipudi@sun.com'/>
   </fix>
   <fix>
    <note>
     Fixed bug in SAX parser that was not forwarding external entity
     declarations in the DTD. (Bug #3392)
    </note>
    <submitter name='Neeraj Bajaj' email='Neeraj.Bajaj@sun.com'/>
   </fix>
   <add>
    <note>
     Separated the XMLDocumentScannerImpl class so that it derives
     from XMLDocumentFragmentScannerImpl which enables an
     application to parse document fragments.
    </note>
    <submitter name='Andy Clark'/>
   </add>
   <add>
    <note>
     Ported the deferred DOM implementation from the Xerces 1.x
     codebase.
    </note>
    <submitter name='Arnaud  Le Hors'/>
   </add>
  </changes>
 </release>
 <release version='&ParserName; 2.0.0 (beta2)'>
  <desc>
   This is primarily a bug fix release. However, a new XNI
   interface and additional documentation have been added.
  </desc>
  <changes>
   <fix>
    <note>
     Fixed bug for when namespace bindings were added as default
     attributes from the DTD.
    </note>
    <submitter name='Andy Clark'/>
   </fix>
   <fix>
    <note>
     Fixed Xerces2 standard components to properly recognize and use
     the features and properties that they are documented to accept.
    </note>
    <submitter name='Andy Clark'/>
   </fix>
   <add>
    <note>
     Added documentation to the XNI Manual for re-using the Xerces2
     parser components.
    </note>
    <submitter name='Andy Clark'/>
   </add>
   <update>
    <note>
     Moved Xerces 1.x to "xerces_j_1" branch and moved Xerces2 to the main 
     trunk of the "xml-xerces" module.
    </note>
    <submitter name='Arnaud  Le Hors'/>
   </update>
   <fix>
    <note>
     Improved ability of document and DTD scanners to perform pull parsing.
    </note>
    <submitter name='Andy Clark'/>
   </fix>
   <fix>
    <note>
     Fixed bug where namespace binder would turn an emptyElement callback into
     startElement and endElement callbacks.
    </note>
    <submitter name='Andy Clark'/>
   </fix>
   <update>
    <note>
     Updated standard parser configuration to separate DTD validation
     and namespace binding in the parsing pipeline.
    </note>
    <submitter name='Andy Clark'/>
   </update>
   <remove>
    <note>
     Removed old XML Schema code that was not being used. This code 
     is intended to be replaced by either a port of the Xerces 1.x 
     XML Schema implementation or by a re-designed, re-implemented
     XML Schema implementation.
    </note>
    <submitter name='Andy Clark'/>
   </remove>
   <fix>
    <note>
     Fixed bug in scanner that allowed the built-in entity references
     to be sent via XNI. The default value for this feature should have
     been false.
    </note>
    <submitter name='Andy Clark'/>
   </fix>
   <fix>
    <note>Fixed several SAX bugs.</note>
    <submitter name='Andy Clark'/>
   </fix>
   <update>
    <note>
     Synchronized DOM implementation code from Xerces 1.x codebase.
    </note>
    <submitter name='Andy Clark'/>
   </update>
  </changes>
 </release>
 <release version='&ParserName; 2.0.0 (beta)'>
  <desc>
   First beta release of the Xerces2 code. Besides numerous bug 
   fixes, this release has changes and additions to XNI. The new
   XNI parser configuration framework has been added in this release.
   Refer to the <link idref='xni'>XNI Manual</link> for complete
   information.
  </desc>
  <changes>
   <add>
    <note>
     Added document and DTD scanner interfaces to XNI to allow
     parser configuration pipelines to be constructed generically.
    </note>
    <submitter name='Andy Clark'/>
   </add>
   <fix>
    <note>
     Fixed bug in DTD grammar for mixed content models that was 
     building the wrong validation content model.
    </note>
    <submitter name='Sandy Gao'/>
   </fix>
   <update>
    <note>
     Removed SAX dependency from XNI framework. Now the only
     dependence on external API such as SAX is in the implementation
     of the AbstractSAXParser and DOMParser so that legacy code
     doesn't break.
    </note>
    <submitter name='Andy Clark'/>
   </update>
   <update>
    <note>
     Rewrote existing documentation, added XNI information, cleaned
     up stylesheets, and converted some docs to use custom DTDs.
    </note>
    <submitter name='Andy Clark'/>
   </update>
   <fix>
    <note>DTD method ordering problem for INCLUDE/IGNORE sections.</note>
    <submitter name='Petr Kuzel'/>
   </fix>
   <update>
    <note>Improved DFA build-time performance.</note>
    <submitter name='ATOZAWA@jp.ibm.com' mailto='ATOZAWA@jp.ibm.com'/>
   </update>
   <update>
    <note>Synchronized with Xerces 1.3.0</note>
    <submitter name='Arnaud  Le Hors'/>
   </update>
  </changes>
 </release>
 <release version='&ParserName; 2.0.0 (alpha)'>
  <desc>Initial alpha release of Xerces2 code.</desc>
 </release>
</releases>
