<?xml version="1.0" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE s1 SYSTEM "sbk:/style/dtd/document.dtd">

<s1 title="TreeWalker Sample">
    <s2 title="TreeWalker">
        <p>The <code>TreeWalkerviewView</code> is an interactive UI sample that displays the DOM
        tree. It show the progress of the tree traversal by moving the selection within the
        DOM tree. Buttons act as a control panel, allowing the user to interactively
        traverse the tree,  remove nodes, add nodes, and view the results immediately in
        the tree. </p>
        <p>The <code>TreeWalkerviewView</code> uses an example filter, 
		<code>NameNodeFilter</code>, that can be controlled from the UI and a 
		<code>DOMTreeFull</code> class that displays the full DOM tree
        with all the nodes.</p>
        <p>The controls are called through to to the corresponding 
		<code>TreeWalker</code> function. If you are familiar with the DOM 
		Level 2 Traversal specification, these controls are
        fairly easy to understand.</p>
        <s3 title="Document Order Traversal Group">
            <ul>
                <li>Next - calls the <code>next()</code> functions and selects 
				the next in the tree.</li>
                <li>Previous - calls the <code>previous()</code> function a and 
				selects the previous node in the DOM tree.</li>
            </ul>
        </s3>
        <s3 title="Walk Group">
	        <p>Parent, Previous Sibling, Next Sibling, First Child, Last Child - call the
	        corresponding function in TreeWalker and show the result as a selected Node.</p>
        </s3>
        <s3 title="Selected Node Group">
            <ul>
                <li>current - set the current node to the selected node.</li>
                <li>remove - remove the selected node and update the tree. 
          		You must press a button to see next or previous node selection.</li>
                <li>add - add a text node. 
          		You must press a button to see next or previous node selection.</li>
            </ul>
        </s3>
        <s3 title="Filter Settings Group">
            <ul>
                <li><code>createNodeTreeWalker</code> - calls the factory 
				method to create a new <code>TreeWalker</code> with the 
				corresponding <code>whatToShow</code> and <code>NodenameFilter</code>
                settings. The selected node becomes the TreeWalker root.</li>
                <li><code>whatToShow</code> - you can singly or multiply select 
				these values by pressing the control key and the 
				<code>TreeWalker</code> is constrained to these types.</li>
                <li><code>NodeNameFilter</code> - an empty string is 
				converted to null and given to the
                <code>NodeNameFilter</code> example filter class provided.</li>
                <ul>
                    <li>An empty string (null) matches ALL nodes.</li>
                    <li>A non-empty string is forced to match node names.</li>
                </ul>
            </ul>
          </s3>     
    </s2>                                                    
    <s2 title="Running TreeWalker">
<source>java dom.traversal.TreeWalkerView &lt;fileName&gt;</source>
    </s2>
</s1>
