<?xml version="1.0" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE s1 SYSTEM "sbk:/style/dtd/document.dtd">

<s1 title="IteratorView Sample">
	<s2 title="IteratorView">
		<p>The <code>IteratorView></code> is an interactive UI sample that displays the DOM tree. It
		shows the progress of the iteration by moving the selection within the DOM tree.
		Buttons act as a control panel, allowing the user to interactively iterate through
		the tree,  remove nodes, add nodes, and view the results immediately in the tree.</p>
		<p>The <code>IteratorView></code> uses an example filter, <code>NameNodeFilter</code>, that can be controlled
		from the UI and a DOMTreeFull class that displays the full DOM tree with all
		the nodes.</p>

		<p>The controls are called through to to the corresponding iterator function. If you
		are familiar with  the DOM Level 2 Traversal specification, these controls are
		fairly easy to understand</p>

		<s3 title="Iterator Group">
		<ul>
			<li>Next - calls the <code>next()</code> functions and selects the next node in the tree.</li>
			<li>Previous - calls the <code>previous()</code> function a and selects the previous node in
     		the tree.</li>
		</ul>
		</s3>
		<s3 title="Selected Node Group">
     	<ul>
			<li><code>remove</code> - remove the selected Node and update the DOM tree. You
    		 must press an iterator button to see next or  previous node selection. </li>
     		<li><code>add</code> - add a text node, to see the results of adding a node on the iterator.
     		position. Again you must first press next or previous </li>
		</ul>
		</s3>
		<s3 title="Iterator Settings Group">
     	<ul>
			<li><code>createNodeIterator</code> - calls the factory method to create a new iterator 
   			with the corresponding <code>whatToShow</code> and <code>NameNodeFilter</code> settings.</li>
				<ul>
					<li>The root is set to be the root of the document, so it 
					starts at the top level each time.</li>
				</ul>
			 
			<li><code>whatToShow</code> - you can singly or multiply select values and the 
			iterator is constrained to showing these types.</li>
			<li><code>NodeNameFilter</code> - An empty string is converted to null and given 
			to the <code>NodeNameFilter</code> class.</li>
				<ul>
					<li>An empty string matches all nodes.</li>
					<li>A non-empty string is forced to match node names.</li>
				</ul>
			
		</ul> 
      </s3>
    </s2>      
	<s2 title="Running IteratorView">                           
<source>java dom.traversal.IteratorView &lt;fileName&gt;</source>
	</s2>
</s1>
