<?xml version="1.0" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE s1 SYSTEM "sbk:/style/dtd/document.dtd">

<s1 title="Samples">
	<s2 title="Introduction">
		<p>There are two new samples to test and demonstrate the new DOM2 
		Transversal implementation: </p>
		<ul>
			<li><link idref="iterator">IteratorView</link></li>
			<li><link idref="tree">TreeWalker</link></li>
		</ul>
	</s2>
	<s2 title="Caveats">
		<note>Make sure that Xerces-J and a JDK are loaded on 
		your computer before running any of the sample parsers.</note>
		<note>Xerces-J: Running the sample applications 
		requires that you have already loaded the Xerces-J software on 
		your computer.</note>
		<note>Java: Running the sample parsers require that your computer has a 
			correctly installed JDK. If you do not already have a JDK already on your computer download
		one from Sun's Java website: <jump href="http://java.sun.com">
		http://java.sun.com</jump> or from IBM's website
		<jump href="http://www.ibm.com/developer/java/">http://www.ibm.com/developer/java/</jump> 
		where you can find an "Enhanced Windows	JDK" that is optimized for the Windows platform. 
		The sample applications
		described in the following pages support Java 1 - JDK 1.1.6. 1.1.7, 1.1.8 or
		Java 2 - JDK 1.2.2. </note>
		<note>UNIX: Command lines in the pages linked below use the Windows path
		separator ';' (semicolon) and directory separator '\' (backslash).. 
		On UNIX, use the ':' (colon) character to separate the JAR files in the classpath,
		and replace Windows directory separator '\' (backslash) with '/' (forward slash).</note>
	</s2>
	<s2 title="IteratorView Sample">
		<p>The IteratorView is an interactive UI sample that displays the DOM tree. It
		shows the progress of the iteration by moving the selection within the DOM tree.
		Buttons act as a control panel, allowing the user to interactively iterate through
		the tree,  remove nodes, add nodes, and view the results immediately in the tree.</p>
		<p>The IteratorView uses an example filter, NameNodeFilter, that can be controlled
		from the UI and a DOMTreeFull class that displays the full DOM tree with all
		the nodes.</p>
		<p><link idref="iterator">IteratorView page</link></p>
	</s2>
	<s2 title="TreeWalker Sample">
		<p>The TreeWalkerviewView is an interactive UI sample that displays the DOM
		tree. It show the progress of the tree traversal by moving the selection within the
		DOM tree. Buttons act as a control panel, allowing the user to interactively
		traverse the tree,  remove nodes, add nodes, and view the results immediately in
		the tree.</p>

		<p>The TreeWalkerviewView uses an example filter, NameNodeFilter, that can be
		controlled from the UI and a DOMTreeFull class that displays the full DOM tree
		with all the nodes.</p>
		<p><link idref="tree">TreeWalkerView page</link></p>
	</s2>
</s1>
