<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE s1 SYSTEM 'dtd/document.dtd'>
<s1 title='SAX Samples'>
 <s2 title='Overview'>
  <p>
   This page documents the various Simple API for XML (SAX)
   samples included with Xerces. Besides being useful programs,
   they can be used as SAX programming examples to learn how to
   program using the SAX API.
  </p>
  <p>SAX samples:</p>
  <ul>
   <li><link anchor='Counter'>sax.Counter</link></li>
   <li><link anchor='DocumentTracer'>sax.DocumentTracer</link></li>
   <li><link anchor='Writer'>dom.Writer</link></li>
  </ul>
  <p>
   Most of the SAX parser samples have a command line option that
   allows the user to specify a different DOM parser to use. In
   order to supply another SAX parser besides the default Xerces
   <code>SAXParser</code>, the parser must implement either the
   <code>org.xml.sax.Parser</code> or <code>org.xml.sax.XMLReader</code>
   interfaces.
  </p>
  <note>
   JAXP could be used instead but this feature is not implemented 
   at this time. Using JAXP would require the user to specify the
   <code>-Djavax.xml.parsers.SAXParserFactory=...</code>
   option to the virtual machine in order to use a different
   SAX parser factory.
  </note>
 </s2>
 <s2 title='sax.Counter'>
  <anchor name='Counter'/>
  <p>
   A sample SAX2 counter. This sample program illustrates how to
   register a SAX2 ContentHandler and receive the callbacks in
   order to print information about the document. The output of
   this program shows the time and count of elements, attributes, 
   ignorable whitespaces, and characters appearing in the document. 
  </p>
  <p>
   This class is useful as a "poor-man's" performance tester to
   compare the speed and accuracy of various SAX parsers. However,
   it is important to note that the first parse time of a parser
   will include both VM class load time and parser initialization
   that would not be present in subsequent parses with the same
   file. 
  </p>
  <note>
   The results produced by this program should never be accepted 
   as true performance measurements.
  </note>
  <s3 title='usage'>
   <source>java sax.Counter (options) uri ...</source>
  </s3>
  <s3 title='options'>
   <table>
    <tr><th>Option</th><th>Description</th></tr>
    <tr><td>-p name</td><td>Select parser by name.</td></tr>
    <tr><td>-x number</td><td>Select number of repetitions.</td></tr>
    <tr><td>-n  | -N</td><td>Turn on/off namespace processing.</td></tr>
    <tr>
     <td>-np | -NP</td>
     <td>
      Turn on/off namespace prefixes.<br/>
      <strong>NOTE:</strong> Requires use of -n.
     </td>
    </tr>
    <tr><td>-v  | -V</td><td>Turn on/off validation.</td></tr>
    <tr>
     <td>-s  | -S</td>
     <td>
      Turn on/off Schema validation support.<br/>
      <strong>NOTE:</strong> Not supported by all parsers.
     </td>
    </tr>
    <tr><td>-m  | -M</td><td>Turn on/off memory usage report.</td></tr>
    <tr><td>-t  | -T</td><td>Turn on/off \"tagginess\" report.</td></tr>
    <tr>
     <td>--rem text</td>
     <td>Output user defined comment before next parse.</td>
    </tr>
    <tr><td>-h</td><td>Display help screen.</td></tr>
   </table>
  </s3>
  <s3 title='notes'>
   <p>
    The speed and memory results from this program should NOT be 
    used as the basis of parser performance comparison! Real 
    analytical methods should be used. For better results, perform
    multiple document parses within the same virtual machine to 
    remove class loading from parse time and memory usage.
   </p>
   <p>
    The "tagginess" measurement gives a rough estimate of the 
    percentage of markup versus content in the XML document. The 
    percent tagginess of a document is equal to the minimum amount 
    of tag characters required for elements, attributes, and 
    processing instructions divided by the total amount of 
    characters (characters, ignorable whitespace, and tag characters)
    in the document.
   </p>
   <p>
    Not all features are supported by different parsers.
   </p>
  </s3>
 </s2>
 <s2 title='sax.DocumentTracer'>
  <anchor name='DocumentTracer'/>
  <p>
   Provides a complete trace of SAX2 events for files parsed. This is
   useful for making sure that a SAX parser implementation faithfully
   communicates all information in the document to the SAX handlers.
  </p>
  <s3 title='usage'>
   <source>java sax.DocumentTracer (options) uri ...</source>
  </s3>
  <s3 title='options'>
   <table>
    <tr><th>Option</th><th>Description</th></tr>
    <tr><td>-p name</td><td>Select parser by name.</td></tr>
    <tr><td>-n | -N</td><td>Turn on/off namespace processing.</td></tr>
    <tr><td>-v | -V</td><td>Turn on/off validation.</td></tr>
    <tr>
     <td>-s | -S</td>
     <td>
      Turn on/off Schema validation support.<br/>
      <strong>NOTE:</strong> Not supported by all parsers.
     </td>
    </tr>
    <tr><td>-h</td><td>Display help screen.</td></tr>
   </table>
  </s3>
 </s2>
 <s2 title='sax.Writer'>
  <anchor name='Writer'/>
  <p>
   A sample SAX2 writer. This sample program illustrates how to
   register a SAX2 ContentHandler and receive the callbacks in
   order to print a document that is parsed.
  </p>
  <s3 title='usage'>
   <source>java sax.Writer (options) uri ...</source>
  </s3>
  <s3 title='options'>
   <table>
    <tr><th>Option</th><th>Description</th></tr>
    <tr><td>-p name</td><td>Select parser by name.</td></tr>
    <tr><td>-n | -N</td><td>Turn on/off namespace processing.</td></tr>
    <tr><td>-v | -V</td><td>Turn on/off validation.</td></tr>
    <tr>
     <td>-s | -S</td>
     <td>
      Turn on/off Schema validation support.<br/>
      <strong>NOTE:</strong> Not supported by all parsers.
     </td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
     <td>-c | -C</td>
     <td>
      Turn on/off Canonical XML output.<br/>
      <strong>NOTE:</strong> This is not W3C canonical output.
     </td>
    </tr>
    <tr><td>-h</td><td>Display help screen.</td></tr>
   </table>
  </s3>
 </s2>
</s1>
