<?xml version="1.0" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE s1 SYSTEM "sbk:/style/dtd/document.dtd">

<s1 title="Samples">
	<s2 title="Introduction">
		<p>There are two new samples to test and demonstrate the new DOM2 
		Traversal implementation: </p>
		<ul>
			<li><link idref="domcount">DOMCount</link></li>
			<li><link idref="domcount">SAXCount</link></li>
			<li><link idref="domwriter">DOMWriter</link></li>
			<li><link idref="domwriter">SAXWriter</link></li>
			<li><link idref="domfilter">DOMFilter</link></li>
			<li><link idref="iterator">IteratorView</link></li>
			<li><link idref="tree">TreeWalker</link></li>
			<li><link idref="treeview">TreeViewer</link></li>
		</ul>
	</s2>
	<s2 title="Caveats">
				<note>&javaparsername;: Running the sample applications 
		requires that you have already loaded the &javaparsername; software on 
		your computer.</note>
		<note>Java: Running the sample applications require that your computer has a 
		correctly installed JDK. If you do not already have a JDK already on 
		your computer download one from Sun&apos;s Java website: 
		<jump href="http://java.sun.com">http://java.sun.com</jump> or from 
		IBM&apos;s website
		<jump href="http://www.ibm.com/developer/java/">http://www.ibm.com/developer/java/</jump> 
		where you can find an &quot;Enhanced Windows JDK&quot; that is optimized 
		for the Windows platform. The sample applications
		described in the following pages support Java 1 - JDK 1.1.6. 1.1.7, 1.1.8 or
		Java 2 - JDK 1.2.2. </note>
		<note>UNIX: Command lines in the pages linked below use the Windows path
		separator &apos;;&apos; (semicolon) and directory separator &apos;\&apos; (backslash).. 
		On UNIX, use the &apos;:&apos; (colon) character to separate the JAR files in the classpath,
		and replace Windows directory separator &apos;\&apos; (backslash) 
		with &apos;/&apos; (forward slash).</note>
	</s2>
	
	<s2 title="DOMCount Sample">
		<p><link idref="domcount">DOMCount</link> parses your input file, 
		and outputs the total parse time, 
		along with counts of elements, attributes, text characters, and ignorable 
		whitespace characters. DOMCount displays errors and 
		warnings that occur during parsing.</p>
		<p>DOMCount uses either the validating or non-validating DOM parser.</p>
	</s2>
	
	<s2 title="SAXCount Sample">
		<p><link idref="domcount">SAXCount</link> parses your input file, 
		and outputs the total parse time, 
		along with counts of elements, attributes, text characters, and 
		ignorable whitespace characters. SAXCount displays errors and 
		warnings that occur during parsing.</p>
		<p>SAXCount uses either the validating or non-validating SAX parser.</p>
	</s2>
	
	<s2 title="DOMWriter Sample">
		<p><link idref="domwriter">DOMWriter</link> parses a file, and 
		prints it out in XML format. 
		The command line option, -c, is used to print files  in 
		"canonical" XML format, so that two XML documents can be compared. 
		They also display any errors or warnings that occurred during the 
		parse. DOMWriter uses either the validating or non-validating DOM parser. 
		DOMWriter also provides a feature to set the output Java encoding 
		through the -e switch.</p>
	</s2>
	
	<s2 title="SAXWriter Sample">
		<p><link idref="domwriter">SAXWriter</link> parses a file, and 
		prints it out in XML format. The command 
		line option, -c, is used to print files  in "canonical" XML format, 
		so that two XML documents can be compared. They also display any 
		errors or warnings that occurred during the parse. SAXWriter uses 
		either the validating or non-validating SAX parser.</p>
	</s2>
	
	<s2 title="DOMFilter Sample">
		<p><link idref="domfilter">DOMFilter</link> shows you how to 
		search for specific elements in 
		your XML document.  It uses <code>getElementsByTagName()</code> 
		to traverse the DOM tree, looking for elements or attributes that 
		match your specification.</p>
	</s2>
		
	<s2 title="IteratorView Sample">
		<p><link idref="iterator">IteratorView</link> is an interactive 
		UI sample that displays the DOM tree. It
		shows the progress of the iteration by moving the selection within the DOM tree.
		Buttons act as a control panel, allowing the user to interactively iterate through
		the tree,  remove nodes, add nodes, and view the results immediately in the tree.</p>
		<p>The <code>IteratorView</code> uses an example filter, 
		<code>NameNodeFilter</code>, that can be controlled
		from the UI and a <code>DOMTreeFull</code> class that displays the full DOM tree with all
		the nodes.</p>
	</s2>
	
	<s2 title="TreeWalker Sample">
		<p><link idref="tree">TreeWalkerviewView</link> is an interactive UI sample that displays the DOM
		tree. It show the progress of the tree traversal by moving the selection within the
		DOM tree. Buttons act as a control panel, allowing the user to interactively
		traverse the tree,  remove nodes, add nodes, and view the results immediately in
		the tree.</p>

		<p>The <code>TreeWalkerviewView</code> uses an example filter, 
		<code>NameNodeFilter</code>, that can be
		controlled from the UI and a <code>DOMTreeFull</code> class that 
		displays the full DOM tree with all the nodes.</p>
	</s2>
	
	<s2 title="Treeviewer Sample">
		<p><link idref="tree">TreeViewer</link> displays the input XML file in a graphical tree-style 
		interface.  It will also highlight lines have well-formedness or validation errors.</p>
	</s2>
</s1>
