<?xml version="1.0" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE s1 SYSTEM "./dtd/document.dtd">
<s1 title="Schema">
	<s2 title="Disclaimer">
		<p>This package contains an implementation of the W3C XML 
		Schema language. This implementation is experimental. The 
		<jump href="http://www.w3.org/XML/Group/Schemas.html">XML Schema</jump> 
		language is still in working draft stage: you 
		should not consider this implementation complete or correct. 
		The limitations of this implementation are detailed below. 
		Please read this document before using this package.</p>
	</s2>
	<s2 title="Introduction">
		<p>This package contains an implementation of a subset of the 
		W3C XML Schema Language as specified in the 7 April 2000
        Working Drafts for <jump
        href="http://www.w3.org/TR/xmlschema-1/">Structures</jump> and
        <jump
        href="http://www.w3.org/TR/xmlschema-2/">Datatypes</jump>. The
        parsers contained in this package are able to read and
        validate XML documents with the grammar specified in either
        DTD or XML Schema format.  There is no functionality for
        accessing typed data.</p> 
		<p>We are making this package available in order to get 
		feedback on the features in the XML Schema language 
		design and on representing an XML document&apos;s grammar 
		as part of the document&apos;s DOM tree. We intend to update 
		this package until it implements all of the functionality 
		of the then current XML Schema Working Draft. If you are 
		interested in a particular unimplemented feature, we welcome 
		your feedback on the &javaparsername; mailing list.</p>
	</s2>
	<s2 title="Limitations">
		<p>The XML Schema implementation in this package is a 
		subset of the features defined in the 7 April 2000 
		XML Schema Working Drafts.</p>
	</s2>
    <s2 title='Components Supported'>
        <ul>
            <li>Element declarations</li>
            <li>Model group definitions: group</li>
            <li>Model groups: all, choice, sequence</li>
            <li>Attribute declarations</li>
            <li>Attribute group definitions</li>
            <li>Simple type definitions</li>
            <li>Complex type definitions</li>
            <li>Wildcards: any</li>
        </ul>
    </s2>
    <s2 title='Components NOT Supported'>
        <ul>
            <li>Wildcards: anyAttribute</li>
            <li>Identity constraints: unique, key, keyref</li>
            <li>Notation declaration</li>
            <li>Annotation (ignored)</li>
        </ul>
    </s2>
    <s2 title='Features Supported'>
        <ul>
            <li>Type derivation</li>
            <li>Anonymous types</li>
            <li>Nested element declaration</li>
            <li>Separate symbol spaces for elements, types, groups, and
                attribute groups</li>
            <li>Equivalency classes</li>
            <li>Target namespace</li>
            <li>"xsi:schemaLocation" and "xsl:noNamespacesSchemaLocation"</li>
            <li>Include</li>
            <li>Import</li>
            <li>"xsi:type"</li>
        </ul>
    </s2>
    <s2 title='Features NOT Supported'>
        <ul>
            <li>Constraints in Chapter 5</li>
            <li>Nullable</li>
            <li>Block</li>
            <li>Abstract</li>
        </ul>
    </s2>
    <s2 title='Datatypes Supported'>
        <ul>
            <li>Built-in simple types (primitive, derived)</li>
            <li>Simple type derivation (restriction, list)</li>
            <li>Regular expressions</li>
            <li>Binary (base64, hex)</li>
            <li>Constraining facets</li>
        </ul>
    </s2>
    <s2 title='Datatypes NOT Supported'>
        <ul>
            <li>Date/time -- ISO8601 (work in progress)</li>
        </ul>
    </s2>
	<s2 title="Other Limitations">
		<p>The schema is specified by the xsi:schemaLocation or
		xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation attribute on the root 
		element of the document. The xsi prefix must be bound to the 
		Schema document instance namespace, as specified by the
		working draft specification. See the sample provided in the
		Usage section.</p>
	</s2>
	<s2 title="Usage">
		<p>In this release, schema validation has been integrated with the 
		regular SAXParser and DOMParser classes. No special classes are 
		required to parse documents that use a schema.</p>
		<p>Documents that use XML Schema grammars specify the location of the
		grammar using an xsi:schemaLocation attribute attached to the root / top-level element 
		in the document. Here is an example with no target namspace: </p>
<source>&lt;document
  xmlns:xsi='http://www.w3.org/1999/XMLSchema-instance'
  xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation='document.xsd'&gt;
...
&lt;/document&gt;</source>
		<p>Here is an example with a target namespace. Note that it is an
		error to specify a different namespace than the target namespace
		defined in Schema.</p>
<source>&lt;document
  xmlns='NS'
  xmlns:xsi='http://www.w3.org/1999/XMLSchema-instance' 
  xsi:schemaLocation='NS document.xsd'&gt;
...
&lt;/document&gt;</source>
		<p>Review the sample file, 'data/personal.xsd' for an example of an XML 
		Schema grammar.</p>
	</s2>
</s1>
